University Library Council and Teams Records UA226
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
University Library Council and Teams Records
1990 -- 2019
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Tisch Library
University Library Council
UA226
0.5 Linear Feet 2 boxes
37 Digital Object(s) 37 digital objects comprising 1,944 files.
607.33 Megabytes
This collection contains the records of the University Library Council and Teams.
Conditions Governing Access
University records are closed for 20 years from the date of their creation. Records older than 20 years that do not pertain to student education, staff and faculty employment and Board of Trustees records are open for research. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by the University Library Council and Teams, 2013 -- 2020, accessions 2013.091, 2014.051, 2015.050, 2016.085, UA-2019-010, and UA-2021-020.
Arrangement
This collection is organized in thirty-two series: Central Database Team; Central Database to E-Resource Management; Circulation and Reserves Team; Citation Management Resources Activation Group; Collections Steering Team; Data Task Force; Digital Asset Management Team; Discovery Layer Task Force; Discovery Platforms Team; Document Delivery Team; Electronic Resources Management Team; Electronic Theses and Dissertation Team; Emerging Technology Activation Group; Hydra Administrative Interface; Integrated Library System Team; Integrated Library Managment System Task Force; Metadata Management Team; Music Library Move; Next Generation Discovery Task Force; Print Copy Contract Task Force; Print-Copy Contract Compliance Team; Publicity and Marketing Team; Statistical Category (SCAT) Team; Scholarly Communication Team; Services Steering Team; Springshare Team; Staff Development Team; Summon Implementation Task Force; University Library Council; Usability Activation Group; Web Resources Team; and Unprocessed accessions.
Biographical / Historical
Directors of the Tufts University Libraries form the University Library Council (ULC), along with the Director of Univesity Library Technology Services, the Director of UIT Educational and Scholarly Technology Services (ex officio) and an Associate Provost (ex officio). The ULC reports to the Provost. The purposes of the ULC are to advance the operations of the libraries for the benefit of faculty, students, staff, administrators and practitioners; to recommend items that affect all Tufts libraries, including librarian promotions, personnel policies, creation of and appointment to university-wide library committees; to develop long-term plans and strategy for library information technology at Tufts; and to develop and implement strategic plans for Tufts University Libraries.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains records created by the University Library Council and the library teams that report to the ULC, including agendas, charges and goals, correspondence, documentation, e-mail lists, meeting minutes, planning documents, and reports.
Academic Support -- Libraries, Galleries, Archives
- Central Database Team, 2005 -- 2007; UA226.000013; 2.3 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 37 files.
  Conditions Governing Access
  20 years from date of creation.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Transferred by Charlotte Keys, Director, Library Technology Services, 2020, accession UA-2021-020.
  Scope and Contents
  Annual reports, charges, agendas and meeting minutes, survey drafts, and spreadsheets created by the Cental Database Team.
  - Central Database Team records, 2005 -- 2007; UA226.000014; 2.3 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 37 files.
- Central Database to E-Resource Management, 2008 -- 2011; UA226.000015; 3.35 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 41 files.
  Meeting minutes, email list archives, taxonomy outlines, and subject heading lists created by the Central Database to E-Resource Management team.
  - Central Database to E-Resource Management records, 2008 -- 2011; UA226.000016; 3.35 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 41 files.
- Circulation and Reserves Team, 2003 -- 2010; UA226.000017; 2.13 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 62 files.
  Goals, charges, and meeting minutes created by the Circulation and Reserves Team.
  - Circulation and Reserves Team records, 2003 -- 2010; UA226.000018; 2.13 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 62 files.
- Citation Management Resources Activation Group, 2011 -- 2017; UA226.000019; 90.77 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 153 files.
  Annual reports, charges and goals, agendas and meeting minutes, email list archives, RefWorks and EndNote documents, surveys, and statistics created by the Citation Management Resources Activation Group.
  - Citation Management Resources Activation Group records, 2011 -- 2017; UA226.000020; 90.77 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 153 files.
- Collections Steering Team, 2000 -- 2010; UA226.000021; 871.5 Kilobytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 31 files.
  Annual reports, goals and charges, and meeting minutes created by the Collections Steering Team.
  - Collections Steering Team records, 2000 -- 2010; UA226.000022; 871.5 Kilobytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 31 files.
- Data Task Force, 2011 -- 2015; UA226.000023; 9.78 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 23 files.
  Annual reports, charges, meeting minutes, email list archives, and statistics created by the Data Task Force.
  - Data Task Force records, 2011 -- 2015; UA226.000024; 9.78 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 23 files.
- Digital Asset Management Team, 2013; UA226.000025; 33.83 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 1 file.
  Digital Asset Management Team meeting minutes.
  - Digital Asset Management Team records, 2013; UA226.000026; 33.83 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 1 file.
- Discovery Layer Task Force, 2012 -- 2013; UA226.000027; 47.3 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 56 files.
  Requests for proposal documents and meeting minutes created by the Discovery Layer Task Force.
  - Discovery Layer Task Force records, 2012 -- 2013; UA226.000028; 47.3 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 56 files.
- Discovery Platforms Team, 2003 -- 2010; UA226.000029; 3.74 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 68 files.
  Annual reports, charges, and meeting minutes created by the Discovery Platforms Team.
  - Discovery Platforms Team records, 2003 -- 2010; UA226.000030; 3.74 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 68 files.
- Document Delivery Team, 2003 -- 2010; UA226.000031; 1.18 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 38 files.
  Annual reports, charges, and meeting minutes created by the Document Delivery Team.
  - Document Delivery Team records, 2003 -- 2010; UA226.000032; 1.18 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 38 files.
- Electronic Resources Management Team, 2004 -- 2010; UA226.000033; 1.05 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 34 files.
  Electronic Resources Management Team meeting minutes.
  - Electronic Resources Management Team records, 2004 -- 2010; UA226.000034; 1.05 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 34 files.
- Electronic Theses and Dissertation Team, 2003 -- 2008; UA226.000035; 2.59 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 51 files.
  Agendas, annual reports, charges and plans, meeting minutes, proposals, and submission documentation created by the Electronic Theses and Dissertation Team.
  - Electronic Theses and Dissertation Team records, 2003 -- 2008; UA226.000036; 2.59 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 51 files.
- Emerging Technology Activation Group, 2006 -- 2010; UA226.000037; 2.05 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 26 files.
  Emerging Technology Activation Group charges and goals, meeting minutes, and DSpace documentation.
  - Emerging Technology Activation Group records, 2006 -- 2010; UA226.000038; 2.05 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 26 files.
- Hydra Administrative Interface, 2012 -- 2014; UA226.000039; 1.17 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 53 files.
  Records related to the development of an administrative interface for the Tufts Fedora repository, including meeting minutes, requirements and specifications, and statements of work for the vendor involved in the project.
  - Hydra Administrative Interface records, 2012 -- 2014; UA226.000040; 1.17 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 53 files.
- Integrated Library System Team, 2003 -- 2005; UA226.000041; 8.87 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 78 files.
  Annual reports, charges, agendas and meeting minutes, articles, and other records related to the Integrated Library System Team.
  - Integrated Library System Team records, 2003 -- 2005; UA226.000042; 8.87 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 78 files.
- Integrated Library Managment System Task Force, 2015 -- 2018; UA226.000043; 181.02 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 314 files.
  Annual reports, charges, documentation, meeting minutes, request for proposal documents, reports, articles, and other records related to the Integrated Library Management System Task Force.
  - Integrated Library Managment System Task Force records, 2015 -- 2018; UA226.000044; 181.02 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 314 files.
- Metadata Management Team, 2004 -- 2011; UA226.000045; 2.01 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 59 files.
  Annual reports, charges, and meeting minutes created by the Metadata Management Team.
  - Metadata Management Team records, 2004 -- 2011; UA226.000046; 2.01 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 59 files.
- Music Library Move, 2012; UA226.000047; 30.78 Kilobytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 27 files.
  Annual reports, charges, meeting minutes, and planning documents created by the Music Library Move Team.
  - Music Library Move records, 2012; UA226.000048; 30.78 Kilobytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 27 files.
- Next Generation Discovery Task Force, 2010 -- 2012; UA226.000049; 1.93 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 18 files.
  Charge, meeting minutes, reports, presentations, and functional requirements created by the Next Generation Discovery Task Force.
  - Next Generation Discovery Task Force records, 2010 -- 2012; UA226.000050; 1.93 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 18 files.
- Print Copy Contract Task Force, 2012; UA226.000051; 9.4 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 11 files.
  Charge, meeting minutes, and contract documents created by the Print Copy Contract Task Force.
  - Print Copy Contract Task Force records, 2012; UA226.000052; 9.4 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 11 files.
- Print-Copy Contract Compliance Team, 2004 -- 2016; UA226.000053; 5.4 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 49 files.
  Annual reports, charges, meeting minutes, and contract documents created by the Print-Copy Contract Compliance Team.
  - Print-Copy Contract Compliance Team records, 2004 -- 2016; UA226.000054; 5.4 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 49 files.
- Publicity and Marketing Team, 2003 -- 2004; UA226.000055; 347.48 Kilobytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 12 files.
  Annual reports, charges, meeting minutes, and project templates created by the Publicity and Marketing Team.
  - Publicity and Marketing Team records, 2003 -- 2004; UA226.000056; 347.48 Kilobytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 12 files.
- Statistical Category (SCAT) team, 2007; UA226.000057; 405.97 Kilobytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 11 files.
  Meeting minutes and call number documentation created by the Statistical Category (SCAT) Team.
  - Statistical Category (SCAT) team records, 2007; UA226.000058; 405.97 Kilobytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 11 files.
- Scholarly Communication Team, 2005 -- 2010; UA226.000059; 1.06 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 29 files.
  Annual reports, charges, and meeting minutes created by the Scholarly Communication Team.
  - Scholarly Communication Team records, 2005 -- 2010; UA226.000060; 1.06 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 29 files.
- Services Steering Team, circa 2002 -- 2018; UA226.001; 115.75 Megabytes; 5 Digital Object(s) 5 digital objects comprising 278 files.
  University records are closed for 20 years from the date of creation. Records older than 20 years that do not pertain to student education, staff and faculty employment and Board of Trustees records are open for research.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged in received order.
  This series contains materials documenting the role and activities of the Services Steering Team, including annual reports, charges and goals, meeting minutes, and shared content such as elists, project management, Boston Library Council information, patron searches (aggregate information only), annual planning, and other material. File structure (Annual reports, Charges and goals, Meeting minutes, and Shared Content) mimics file structure on the Services Steering Team area of Libstaff (Sharepoint instance). Member lists are included; link lists and announcements are not.
  Transferred by University Library Council and Teams, 2017, accession UA-2019-010, and 2020, accession UA-2021-020.
  Biographical / Historical
  The Services Steering Team was created to provide strategic planning and direction for the delivery of shared resources and services; offer a common forum to discuss library service issues and assign specific actions to address these issues in a timely fashion; solicit and communicates ULC priorities to the SST subgroups; channel the needs, priorities and outcomes of the work of the SST subgroups to ULC and other ULC groups as appropriate; and enable sharing of resources and expertise across the libraries.
  - Annual Reports, 2002 -- 2018; UA226.001.00001; 11 Digital Object(s); 0.9 Megabytes
    Annual reports from FY03 through FY17.
  - Charges and Goals, 2003 -- 2018; UA226.001.00002; 19 Digital Object(s); 0.7 Megabytes
    Charges and goals from FY04 through FY17.
  - Meeting Minutes, 2002 -- 2017; UA226.001.00003; 139 Digital Object(s); 4.5 Megabytes
    Meeting minutes from FY02 through FY17.
  - Shared Content, 2003 -- 2016; UA226.001.00004; 104 Digital Object(s); 109.5 Megabytes
    Elists, project management, BLC, patron searches, annual planning, and other shared content.
  - Services Steering Team records, 2008 -- 2017; UA226.000012; 148 Kilobytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 5 files.
    Meeting minutes, announcements, patron searches, and Boston Library Consortium (BLC) documents created by the Services Steering Team.
- Springshare Team, 2009 -- 2019; UA226.000061; 41.61 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 112 files.
  Annual reports, charges and goals, email list archives, LibGuides documentation, and statistics created by the Springshare Team.
  - Springshare Team records, 2009 -- 2019; UA226.000062; 41.61 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 112 files.
- Staff Development Team, 2003 -- 2010; UA226.000063; 2.41 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 61 files.
  Annual reports, charges, and meeting minutes of the Staff Development Team.
  - Staff Development Team records, 2003 -- 2010; UA226.000064; 2.41 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 61 files.
- Summon Implementation Task Force, 2013 -- 2015; UA226.000065; 25.95 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 30 files.
  Email list archives and Summon implementation documents created by the Summon Implementation Task Force.
  - Summon Implementation Task Force records, 2013 -- 2015; UA226.000066; 25.95 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 30 files.
- University Library Council, 2001 -- 2014; UA226.000067; 5.72 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 126 files.
  Meeting minutes, strategic plans, training documents, goals, reports, and related documents created by the University Library Council.
  - University Library Council records, 2001 -- 2014; UA226.000068; 5.72 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 126 files.
- Usability Activation Group, 2006 -- 2010; UA226.000069; 169.05 Kilobytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 4 files.
  Usability Activation Group meeting minutes.
  - Usability Activation Group records, 2006 -- 2010; UA226.000070; 169.05 Kilobytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 4 files.
- Web Resources Team, 2006 -- 2009; UA226.000071; 3.14 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 49 files.
  Agendas, meeting minutes, charges, and progress updates created by the Web Resources Team.
  - Web Resources Team records, 2006 -- 2009; UA226.000072; 3.14 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 49 files.
- Additional accessions, UA226.000009
  - Electronic Dissertations and Theses Team and Services Steering Team, 2003 -- 2011; UA226-001 (Box 1)
    Files of the Electronic Dissertations and Theses Team, 2003-2008, and Services Steering Team, 2010-2011
  - ULC general and Lending Team, 1990 -- 2000; UA226-002 (Box 2)
    From Charlotte Keys
  - Electronic Dissertations and Theses team, 2004 -- 2008; UA226-003
    Open for research.
    Team created by ULC in 2004ish to receive and provide access to ETDs electronically through ProQuest.
  - Libstaff backup from disk, 1995 -- 2005; UA226-004